<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<language name="lang_en">
	<menu>
		<main>
			Bombic 2
			<resume_game>Resume game</resume_game>
			<new_game>New game</new_game>
			<load_game>Load game</load_game>
			<save_game>Save game</save_game>
			<deathmatch>Deathmatch</deathmatch>
			<options>Options</options>
			<quit>Quit</quit>
		</main>
		<new_game>
			New game
			<play>Play</play>
			<players_count>Players count</players_count>
			<episode>Episode</episode>
			<back>Back</back>
		</new_game>
		<load_game>
			Load game
			<filetype>Bombic saved game XML</filetype>
			<directory>Directory</directory>
			<file>File</file>
			<type>Type</type>
			<ok>Load</ok>
			<cancel>Cancel</cancel>
		</load_game>
		<save_game>
			Save game
			<filetype>Bombic saved game XML</filetype>
			<directory>Directory</directory>
			<file>File</file>
			<type>Type</type>
			<ok>Save</ok>
			<cancel>Cancel</cancel>
		</save_game>
		<deathmatch>
			Deathmatch
			<play>Play</play>
			<maps>
				Choose map
				<submenu>
					Choose deathmatch map
					<filetype>Bombic map XML</filetype>
					<directory>Directory</directory>
					<file>File</file>
					<type>Type</type>
					<ok>Choose</ok>
					<cancel>Cancel</cancel>
					<map_error>File does not represent Bombic map.</map_error>
					<file_name_error>Filename is too long, rename them first.</file_name_error>
				</submenu>
			</maps>
			<bonuses>
				Bonuses
				<submenu>
					Bonuses in deathmatch
					<ok>OK</ok>
				</submenu>
			</bonuses>
			<players_count>Players count</players_count>
			<win_points>Win points</win_points>
			<creatures>Creatures</creatures>
			<bombs_at_end>Limited deathmatch</bombs_at_end>
			<back>Back</back>
		</deathmatch>
		<options>
			Options
			<language>Language</language>
			<controls>
				Controls
				<submenu>
					Controls
					<player>Player</player>
					<left>Left</left>
					<right>Right</right>
					<up>Up</up>
					<down>Down</down>
					<plant>Plant bomb</plant>
					<timer>Timer</timer>
					<ok>OK</ok>
					<press_key>Press any KEY to use&#10;or ESCAPE to cancel.</press_key>
				</submenu>
			</controls>
			<speed>Game speed</speed>
			<presumptions>Explosion presumptions</presumptions>
			<split_screen>Split screen</split_screen>
			<fullscreen>Play in fullscreen</fullscreen>
			<sound>Sound enabled</sound>
			<save>Save</save>
			<cant_set_lang>Sorry, I can&apos;t set this language.</cant_set_lang>
		</options>
	</menu>
	<game>
		<debug>
			Debug
			<after>
				After debug
			</after>
		</debug>
		<!-- 515 -->
		<death>
			Hek Uh Uh Chrchl Chrchl... Next time...&#10;
			chrchl uh uh... I have to be... hek...&#10;
			... more careful... aaahhrrr...&#10;
			... I can see the light...
		</death>

		<!-- 500 -->
		<newspaper>
			Once I was reading my newspapers. My favourite&#10;
			Daily Bomb. I found an advertisement:&#10;
			&quot;We are searching for a courageous one&#10;
			for trip to the forest. We want him to deliver&#10;
			a message to the hermit. The reward shall be&#10;
			a chest of Becherovka&quot;.&#10;
			Well, I had nothing else to do so I decided to go...&#10;
		</newspaper>

		<!-- 501 -->
		<first_in_forest>
			As soon as I reached the forest, i was attacked by&#10;
			some enemy creatures. Some disgusting flying heads.&#10;
			They scared me. But I had my bombs ready to use.&#10;
			They had no chance.
		</first_in_forest>

		<!-- 502 -->
		<deep_in_forest>
			I&apos;m going deeper and I&apos;m thinking&#10;
			it is going to be a hard job.&#10;
			They forgot to mention these creatures&#10;
			in the advertisement.&#10;
			Someone should come here and clean it up.&#10;
			Fortunately I have found some bonuses on the way.&#10;
			They have upgraded my bombs.&#10;
			We will see how it will continue.....
		</deep_in_forest>

		<!-- 503 -->
		<stupid_creatures>
			There are more and more of those stupid creatures&#10;
			along the way. But I met the Slimer today.&#10;
			He isn&apos;t as stupid as I thought.&#10;
			Becherovka is the only thing that makes me continue&#10;
			in this quest where my life is at stake.&#10;
			I hope I&apos;m going to live long enough to tell about it.
		</stupid_creatures>

		<!-- 504 -->
		<winnersculpture>
			Great statue of Bombers. This group of statues&#10;
			was probably built to commemorate some great bomber&#10;
			warrior. Unfortunately his name is unreadable. I wish&#10;
			I had his skills. It would be very useful.&#10;
			Wait. This memorial isn&apos;t on the map!&#10;
			I hope they have given me the right map.
			<!-- 505 -->
			<after>
				At last. I have found the hermit&apos;s cabin but&#10;
				nobody was there. It was empty. Do you understand it?&#10;
				The whole effort was for nothing. There are only&#10;
				enemy creatures all around. There was one extremely&#10;
				strong wondering infront of the cabin. Wow!&#10;
				I have just found some supplies of Becherovka.&#10;
				I took the liberty of keeping some of the bottles.&#10;
				Just for taste...
			</after>
		</winnersculpture>

		<!-- 507 -->
		<zzz>
			Zzzzzzzzz, zzzzzzzzz,zzzzzzzz...
		</zzz>

		<!-- 508 -->
		<ghost_in_dream>
			It was a dream. Almost a nightmare.&#10;
			The surrounding was beautiful.&#10;
			But what about the ghost that was there.&#10;
			Fortunately it wasn&apos;t a hard job to deal with.&#10;
			I should stop with this bombing stuff.&#10;
			It starts getting into my dreams.&#10;
			&#10;
			The hermit disappeared so I&apos;m definitely not staying&#10;
			any longer on this place. It is far too dangerous&#10;
			to stay here and wait. Let&apos;s go home.&#10;
			It should be an easy way back.
		</ghost_in_dream>

		<!-- 510 -->
		<lost_in_forest>
			It doesn&apos;t look familiar here. I have a bad feeling&#10;
			about this. I sure haven&apos;t gone this way the first time.&#10;
			Noooo - I&apos;m lost. Now what? I have got a good idea.&#10;
			I&apos;ll keep heading in this direction and hopefully&#10;
			I&apos;ll reach the end of this forest.
			<!-- 511 -->
			<after>
				Poor fellow hermit. The Cloud probably killed him.&#10;
				Now I know why the message for him was: &quot;Don&apos;t do it.&#10;
				It is too dangerous.&quot;
			</after>
		</lost_in_forest>

		<!-- 512 -->
		<chest>
			There in front of me I see a chest. It is probably&#10;
			the one, for which the hermit was searching for. Since&#10;
			I already found it I&apos;ll look what&apos;s inside.&#10;
			But I have to get rid of that ghost who is guarding it first.&#10;
			I have a feeling I had a dream about this creature.
			<!-- 513 -->
			<after>
				It was a mortal kombat. When my pulse returned to normal,&#10;
				I realized, that the chest is empty. But I have found&#10;
				footprints leading to the cave. Let&apos;s go there...
			</after>
		</chest>

		<!-- 520 -->
		<where_is_treasure>
			I wonder where does this cave lead to. I&apos;ll reveal&#10;
			it soon. The guy who stole the treasure from the chest&#10;
			will probably be there.
		</where_is_treasure>

		<!-- 521 -->
		<complex_of_corridors>
			It is unbelievable. It looks like this small cave&#10;
			is in fact a large complex full of corridors. I have no&#10;
			idea, why someone created this complex in the middle of&#10;
			a forest. I&apos;ll try to find out.&#10;
			Unfortunately it looks like I&apos;m not alone here.&#10;
			I met my old &quot;friends&quot; - again.&#10;
			But I also found some good stuff - good stuff&#10;
			for finishing them off.
		</complex_of_corridors>

		<!-- 522 -->
		<trap>
			I was almost killed by some rolling stones with spikes.&#10;
			They change direction when they reach a wall - maybe it&apos;s&#10;
			some sort of a trap ??!! But what is it supposed to guard&#10;
			My old enemies disappeared as well. Only some of them&#10;
			probably entered the cave from the forest entrance.
		</trap>

		<!-- 523 -->
		<machine>
			I have found a mysterious machine. I have tried to&#10;
			explore it further, but have been unable to recognize it.&#10;
			I wish I paid more attention while studying at school.&#10;
			My old enemies are history.
		</machine>

		<!-- 524 -->
		<new_enemy>
			I crossed paths with a new kind of enemy. It&apos;s size&#10;
			and shape is similar to the one in the forest, but it&#10;
			seems to be mutated somehow. It has a red color and it&apos;s&#10;
			much harder to kill. If I don&apos;t find a way out of this&#10;
			place - well, I&apos;ll go nuts that&apos;s for sure.
			<!-- 525 -->
			<after>
				Oh. What have we here? Hmmm. What a pleasent smell !!!&#10;
				How could someone possibly forget something&#10;
				like this over here. It won&apos;t stay here&#10;
				for long that&apos;s for sure...
			</after>
		</new_enemy>

		<!-- 526 -->
		<tasty>
			Mmm. Tasty... yammy...
		</tasty>

		<!-- 527 -->
		<favourite_drink>
			It looks like my favourite drink has special effect on me.&#10;
			If I&apos;m right then I won&apos;t like this.
		</favourite_drink>

		<!-- 528 -->
		<special_trap>
			It&apos;s starting to be somewhat damaged in here. I&apos;m surely&#10;
			getting nearer to the end. Hope it won&apos;t be my end though.&#10;
			I saw a special trap.&#10;
			It has a better software and it&apos;s a lot faster.
		</special_trap>

		<!-- 529 -->
		<nightmare_monster>
			Oh my... my nightmare monster. Now you&apos;ll see what my&#10;
			kamikadze attack looks like you old TV. Only one of us&#10;
			can get through this alive and I&apos;m not planning on dying.
			<!-- 530 -->
			<after>
				At last. I can see the sunshine again. And now let&apos;s&#10;
				go home - to our local pub.&#10;
				I&apos;m looking forward to seeing my old friends.
			</after>
		</nightmare_monster>


		<!-- 540 -->
		<sunshine>
			I was expecting a different feeling, but at least&#10;
			the Sun is shining and I can breath fresh air again.&#10;
			I hope I&apos;ll get to the civilization soon. I&apos;m missing&#10;
			TV and video. And I want hamburger and cola
			...and my favourite Becherovka.
		</sunshine>

		<!-- 541 -->
		<boring_creatures>
			Oh no. These red creatures are boring. I wonder&#10;
			why there isn&apos;t any more powerfull creature. These&#10;
			are really stupid. My grandmother would kill them&#10;
			easily.
		</boring_creatures>

		<!-- 542 -->
		<preadator>
			Ha the predator is here. He doesn&apos;t look like my&#10;
			grandma but he is strong enough. I saw him eating&#10;
			the red creature but it saw me and&#10;
			it started to hunt me. Fortunately it is a bit slow.
		</preadator>

		<!-- 543 -->
		<it_almost_got_me>
			I have seen something like this before. Oh yes. This&#10;
			creature was in front of hermit&apos;s cabin and it almost got me.&#10;
			I hope they are rare. I don&apos;t want to face them any more.&#10;
			I&apos;ll rather try to avoid contact with them.
		</it_almost_got_me>

		<!-- 544 TODO length-->
		<broken_boat>
			It looks like someone sure didn&apos;t know what how to ride on&#10;
			a boat!. And when they got out the desert didn&apos;t give them&#10;
			much of a chance either. There is something written on the hull.&#10;
			&quot;Expedition sea of wishes. Happiness for everyone&quot;.&#10;
			What does it mean? Who could be searching for sea in the middle&#10;
			of a desert?
			<!-- 545 -->
			<after>
				Wow. Could I have found the sea of wishes. Judging from it&apos;s color&#10;
				it is obvious that it isn&apos;t water.&#10;
				Do you smell it? Oh yes. This one smells much better...
			</after>
		</broken_boat>

		<!-- 546 -->
		<chrr>
			Chrrrrr Chrrrrrr Chrrrrr...
		</chrr>

		<!-- 547 -->
		<dont_give_up>
			Dreams are such a good thing. At least I know what kind of trouble&#10;
			am I getting into. I can&apos;t do much with it. But I won&apos;t give up.&#10;
			I won&apos;t let anyone kill me easily.
		</dont_give_up>

		<!-- 548 -->
		<something_found>
			Look what I have found. A well. But it has run dry. Caravans&#10;
			probably use to travel this way... I&apos;m getting nearer to&#10;
			civilization. Suddenly I&apos;m in much better mood...
		</something_found>

		<!-- 549 -->
		<theend>
			As I&apos;m watching him he looks like a realy bad guy. He sure&#10;
			doesn&apos;t look friendly. I&apos;ll try to negotiate - using my bombs&#10;
			of course.
			<!-- 550 -->
			<after>
				The Great evil hero was guarding the sea of wishes.&#10;
				No I can wish for something. The only thing I can think of is this:&#10;
				&#10;
				BECHEROVKA FOR EVERYONE AND FOR FREE. DON&apos;T LET ANYONE LEAVE EMPTY HANDED
			</after>
		</theend>
	</game>
</language>